Finding Aid for the Harold Stirling Vanderbilt Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Harold Stirling Vanderbilt Papers
undated
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0468
18.36 linear feet
Biographical Sketch
1884 - July 6, Harold S. Vanderbilt born to William Kissam Vanderbilt and Alva Erskine Smith (later Mrs. O.H.P. Belmont) at Oakdale, N.Y.
1901 Gertrude Lewis Pancoast Conaway born
1903 Vanderbilt graduated from St. Mark's School, Southborough, Massachusetts. First race, on the RELIANCE.
1907 Graduated from Harvard University.
1910 Cruise on the VAGRANT. Won the Bermuda Race. West Indies Cruise. 1917 - Patrolled waters from London to Nantucket for the U.S. Navy.
1921 Won the Astor Cup.
1922 Won the Astor Cup; King's Cup.
1925 Invented'contract bridge. King's Cup.
1928 Vanderbilt Cup established.
1930 Successfully defended the America's Cup against Britain's Sir Thomas Lupton, ENTERPRISE vs. SHAMROCK V
1932 King's Cup. Vanderbilt Cup.
1933 Vanderbilt married Gertrude Conaway in New York.
1934 Defended the America's Cup against Britain's T.O.M. Sopwith, RAINBOW vs. ENDEAVOR
1935 Astor Cup. 1937 - America's Cup, RANGER vs. ENDEAVOR II. 1942 - Started farming in Virginia.
1950 Elected to the Board of Trust, Vanderbilt University.
1955 Became President of the Board of Trust. 1967 - Financed the America's Cup defender INTREPID. Retired as President of the Board of Trust.
1970 July 4, Vanderbilt died
1978 August 6, Gertrude Vanderbilt died.
- Personal and family material: Correspondence, newspaper clippings (Box 1)
- Appraisals of residences, certificates, awards (Box 2)
- Vanderbilt University material: Correspondence, newspaper clippings (Box 3)
- Contract Bridge material: Incoming and Outgoing Correspondence (Box 4)
- Contract Bridge material: Drafts for rules revisions, scrapbooks (Box 5)
- Yachting material: Incoming Correspondence (Box 6)
- Yachting material: Outgoing Correspondence, newspaper articles (Box 7)
- Yachting material: Racing rules,; Appeals to the Racing Committee (Box 8)
- Yachting material: Racing rules, drafts and reports of the Racing Committee (Box 9)
- Yachting material: Log books (Box 10-12)
- Yachting scrapbooks, 1922-1958. (except 1930, see boxes 26 and 27) (Box 13-16)
- Scrapbook of Commodore Vanderbilt's Steamboat activities', H.S. Vanderbilt's World War I scrapbook; Plans for McGugin Center, Vanderbilt University (Box 17)
- Sheet music (Box 18)
- Books, Dairies, Charts (Box 19)
- Trophies won by John Conaway and Gertrude Conaway (Box 20)
- >todel plane 22-24 Museum pieces (Box 21)
- Large pictures, certificates, awards (Box 25)
- 1930 scrapbook of the America 1 s Cup Race 2/6 Resolution by the Board of Trust, 1968, Printed (Box 26, 27)
- Resolution by the Board of Trust, 1971, Printed (Box 2/7)
- Two sketches of women (Box 2/8)
- Sketches of two ships by Mario Valenzuela (Box 2/9)
- Color drawirlg (Box 2/10)
- Marriage license John L. Conaway and Mary Faris Pancoast Certificate of Baptism - Gertrude Lewis Pancoast Conaway Marriage license - Harold and Gertrude Vanderbilt Marriage Service of Harold and Gertrude Vanderbilt (Box 2/11)
- The Naval Relief Society, Certificate of Recognition (4) (Box 2/12)
- Certificate for gift of the Marble House, 1966 Certificate from the Belgian King Albert, 1925, to Frederick Vanderbilt (Box 2/13)
- Sousa March "American Cup Defense" dedicated to Harold Stirling Vanderbilt (Box 2/14)
- Vanderbilt University Correspondence 1 General - Incoming (Box 3/1)
- Vanderbilt University Correspondence, General - Outgoing (Box 3/2)
- Hospital West Wing (Box 3/3)
- Newspaper clippings (Box 3/4)
- Integration Correspondence - Incoming (Box 3/5)
- Integration Correspondence - Outgoing | (Box 3/6)
- Integration Material, Board of Trust (Box 3/7)
- Lawson Affair (Box 3/8)
- Selection of Chancellor Correspondence - Incoming (Box 3/9)
- Selection of Chancellor Correspondence - Outgoing (Box 3/10)
- Committee to choose a new Chancellor; Board of Trust (Box 3/11)
- Newpaper clippings: marriage and honeymoon (Box 1/1)
- Essay: "Harold S. Vanderbilt -- Sportsman" (Box 1/2)
- Pictures and sketches (Box 1/3)
- Newspaper clippings (Box 1/4)
- Four Sports Illustrated Articles.on Harold S. Vanderbilt, 1956 (Box 1/5)
- Obituaries for Harold and Gertrude Vanderbilt (Box 1/6)
- Correspondence of Gertrude Vanderbilt and Robert L. Garland (Box 1/7)
- Consuelo Vanderbilt Balsan, typescrpt of an article in Life (Box 1/8)
- Essays published in Life on the Vanderbilt Family, by Wixen. (Box 1/9)
- Two samples of the Commodore's Signature (Box 1/10)
- Drawings of a yacht, by Wilson (Box 1/11)
- General Correspondence, Incoming (Box 1/12)
- General Correspondence, Outgoing (Box 1/13)
- Biltmore House material (Box 1/14)
- "Proposal for Airport and Operating Company" (Box 1/15)
- Index of Books in the library of H.S. Vanderbilt (Box 1/16)
- Newspaper clippings — the Talbot affair (Box 1/17)
- Newspaper Clippings -- Contributions made to Harvard University (Box 1/18)
- Information on the Falcon Airline Service for Gertrude Vanderbilt (Box 1/19)
- Mayor of Manalapan election, vote tally (Box 1/20)
- Two engraVed portraits of William H. Vanderbilt, Sr. (Box 1/21)
- Appraisal of Residence at Manalapan (Box 2/1)
- Appraisal of "Eastover" the Residence at Manalapan (Box 2/2)
- Appraisal of Farm Property at Hypoluxe, Florida (Box 2/3)
- Appraisal of Residence at 435 East 52nd Street, New York (Box 2/4)
- Appraisal of Rockcliff, Newport, Rhode Island (Box 2/5)
- Plans for the installation ceremony of Alexander Heard (Box 3/12)
- Newspaper clippings, Alexander Heard (Box 3/13)
- Newspaper clippings, HSV's resignation from the Board of Trust (Box 3/14)
- Newspaper clippings, HSV honored (Box 3/15)
- Vanderbilt Speeches and Introductions (Box 3/16)
- Newspaper clippings — Vanderbilt Family Reunion (Box 3/17)
- Correspondence - J.H. Kirkland and William K. Vanderbilt (Box 3/18-19)
- Correspondence - Alexander Heard and Gertrude (Box 3/20)
- Incoming Correspondence, Contract Bridge (Box 4/1-4)
- Outgoing Correspondence, Contract Bridge (Box 4/5-8)
- Handwritten notes on Bridge (Box 4/9)
- Bridge notes (Box 4/10)
- Manuscript of Bridge (typed) (Box 4/11)
- Bridge Pamphlets, notes (Box 4/12)
- Newspaper clippings (Box 4/13)
- Proposed draft for Revision of 1948-1949 Laws (Box 5/1)
- Committee Drafts, 1961, March 1962 (Box 5/2)
- Memoranda for Drafting Committee, 1961 (Box 5/3)
- First draft of Laws of Duplicate Contract Bridge (Box 5/4)
- Contract Bridge Rules (Box 5/5)
- Draft #5 Suggested Revisions of Rules (Box 5/6)
- Scrapbook, 1929/30 (Box 5/7)
- Scrapbook, 1932/33 (Box 5/8)
- Scrapbook, 1936 (Box 5/9)
- Scrapbook, 1937-39 (Box 5/10)
- Scrapbook, 1940-41 (Box 5/11)
- Summary of the Vanderbilt One-Club System (Box 5/12)
- Essay on the Vanderbilt Cup (Box 5/13)
- Letter to Whist Club members (Box 5/14)
- Incoming Correspondence, Yachting (Box 6/1-10)
- Outgoing Correspondence, Yachting (Box 7/1-7)
- Correspondence concerning new editions of yachting books James J. Beha and J.T. Claiborne (Box 7/8)
- New Yachting Rules 1944 (Scrapbook) (Box 7/9)
- Yachting - nevqpaper articles (Box 7/10)
- Yachting Rules, Nov. 1959-May 1960 (Box 8/1)
- Yachting Rules, June 1960-March 1963 (Box 8/2)
- Yachting Rules, Undated (Box 8/3)
- Yachting Memorabilia (Box 8/4)
- New York Yacht Club Appeals Committee, Sept. 1960- Aug. 1963 (Box 8/5)
- 1967 America's Cup program (Box 8/6)
- "The Match for the America's Cup" 1930. Boston. The Sportsman (Box 8/7)
- America's Cup pamphlet. Illustrations (Box 8/8)
- "Sailing Beauty" Photographic Essay, 1958 (Box 8/9)
- Proof sheets for the America's Cup Races, Herbert L-Stone and William H. Taylor (Box 8/10)
- Ad for America's Cup Series by Hedwin (Box 8/11)
- Yachting articles. (Box 8/12-13)
- Gertrude C. Vanderbilt's Scrapbook on Yachting (Box 8/14)
- North American Yacht Racing Union. Decisions on Appeals (Box 9)
- Appeal no. 71 Revisions in Pencil. (Box 9)
- NAYRU. Pertinent Decisions of the Appeals Committee. Appeals through 83. Published, Oct. 1961 (Box 9)
- NAYRU. Pertinent Decisions of the Appeals Committee. Appeals through 52. Published, May 1958 (Box 9)
- NAYRU. Decisions on Appeals. Appeal No. 76. Pagan vs. Westerly (Box 9)
- NAYRU. Decision on Appeals. Appeal No. 82 (Box 9)
- Yacht Racing Association of Long Island Sound. Appeal No. 6 (Rule 34.1 (b) iii) (Box 9)
- NAYRU. Report of the Annual Meeting of the NAYRU, Jan. 18, 1961 (Box 9)
- New York Yacht Club. Report of the Race Committee, 1961 (Box 9)
- NAYRU. Don A, Appeal No. 84 (Box 9)
- "Conditions Governing the Races for the America's Cup, 1962" (Box 9)
- NAYRU. Decision on Appeals Nos. 94,95, 96, 97, and 98, Jan. 6, 1964
- NAYRU. Report of the Annual Meeting of the NAYRU., Jan. 22, 1964 (Box 9)
- America's Cup Race, 1964. Racing Instructions (Box 9)
- NYYC. Use of Time Allowances in Day and Distant Races, 1962 (Box 9)
- I Sept 10, 1959. Draft of "A Suggested Revision of the 1959 IYRU and NAYRU Yacht Racing Rules" Recommended by the NAYRU for adoption in Nov. 1959 and Notes on Rules prepared by "Harold S. Vanderbilt" (Box 9/1)
- NAYRU. 1960 Rules. Draft of Sept 24, 1959, Bemis' copy (Box 9/2)
- NAYRU. 1960 Rules Draft of Sept 24, 1959 HSV Copy (Box 9/3)
- NAYRU. 1960 Rules. Draft of, Oct. 1, 1959 (Box 9/4)
- NAYRU. 1960 Rules. Draft of, Oct. 1, 1959 (Box 9/5)
- NAYRU. 1960 Rules Draft of Oct. 7, 1959 (and Oct. 8, H.S.V corrected copy) (Box 9/6)
- NAYRU. 1960 Rules Draft of Oct. 7, 1959, (and Oct. 8, meeting copy, Oct. 13, and Oct 22) (Box 9/7)
- Suggested Revision of the NAYRU 1959 Racing Rules. Prepared in 1959 by the Rules Committee of the NAYRU (Box 9/8)
- Revision of the NAYRU 1959 Racing Rules (Box 9/9)
- Definitions and Sections I & II of Sailing Rules when Yachts meet. Prepared by Harold S. Vanderbilt, May 26, 1960 (Box 9/10)
- Definitions and Right of Way Rules as of 6/3/60 (Box 9/II)
- Draft of Definitions and Right of Way Rules as prepared by Harold S. Vanderbilt, June 22, 1960 (Box 9/12)
- Proposals for Amendments to the 1959 Yacht Racing Rules of the International Yacht Racing Union. NAYRU. Appeal #74 10 RANGER sailbook, 1937 Vim Sail and Log Book, 1939 Vagrant, 1913 The Log of the Alva, 1891 1 V Coil (1 q'- >v ' 1 ' The Log of the Blue Dolphin to the West Indies, 1931 Log of the Vagrant, 1910 Log of the Vagrant West Indies Cruise, 1916 (Box 9/13)
- Log of the Last Buccaneer, Mississippi Voyage, 1951 (Box 10-4)
- Log of the Great African Cruise - R.M.S. Caronia 1950 (Box 10-5)
- Itinerary prepared for Harold S. Vanderbilt, 1955 (Box 10-6)
- Log of the Convair, 1949 (Box 10-7)
- "Cruise of the Constellation to the West Indies, Winter of 1919" (Box 11)
- Photo Album of Boat trips: Barge canal (Erie?) 1951 Mohawk River, Lake Seneca Tonawanda, Niagara River On the Mohawk R. On the Campus of Cornell Niagara Falls (Box 11)
- Log of the Argosy Mediterranean Cruise from Cannes. Aug 1933. (Honeymoon Cruise) (Box 11)
- Prologue to the Log of the Rex (Argosy) cruise to Europe (Honeymoon) (Box 110)
- Log of the Versatile, first four volumes, Sept 1950 - April 1951 to Aug 1951 to Feb. 1952 to July 1952 (Box 11)
- Log of the Versatile (Box 12)
- V. To, Dec. 1952 (Box 12)
- VI. to, June 1953 (Box 12)
- VII. to, Aug. 1954 (Box 12)
- VIII. to May 1955 (Box 12)
- IX. to April 1956 (Box 12)
- X. to March 1957 (Box 12)
- XI. to May 1958 (Box 12)
- XII. to Oct. 1958 (Box 12)
- XIII. to Sept. 1959 (Box 12)
- XIV. to Aug. 1960 (Box 12)
- 12-1 Versatile, charts (Box 12-1)
- (Paige box) Yachting Scrapbooks, 1922 - 1934 (except 1930, see boxes 26 & 27) (Box 13)
- (Paige box) Yachting Scrapbooks, 1934 - 1937 (Box 14)
- (Paige box) Yachting Scrapbooks, 1937 - 1939 (Box 15)
- Yachting Scrapbooks, 1939 - 58 "Vim" at Harwick, 1939 (Box 16)
- Plans for McGugin Center, Vanderbilt University Campus (Box 17/1)
- Scrapbook, Commodore Vanderbilt's Activities (Box 17/2)
- Harold S. Vanderbilt's World War I scrapbook (Box 17/3)
- Sheet Music (Box 18)
- Book of Common Prayer, 1892 (Box 19)
- Hymnal, 1892 (Box 19)
- Diary and Manual of the Real Estate Board of New York; Inc. 1914, 1915, 1917, 1923, 19247 1928, 1929, 1931 (Box 19)
- "A Personal Book for Executives" 1927 (Box 19)
- Tyrrel Diary, 1933 (Box 19)
- Daily Reminder, 1922, 1921 (Box 19)
- Agenda, 1910 (Box 19)
- Lockheed Super-electra, notebook of flights, April 10, 1938 May 9, 1939 (Box 19)
- Four photos of jets (Box 19)
- Advertisment brochure for Lockheed "Jet Star" domestic Route Study (Box 19)
- Advertisement booklet for Grumman Gulfstream (Box 19)
- Interior design plans for plane^Horton and Horton (Box 19)
- Plans for jet (Box 19)
- Lockheed plans (Box 19)
- Jet-Star model Specification L (Box 19)
- 19 Map of Martha's Vineyard to Blpch Island (Box 19)
- Pilot Chart of the Upper Air- North Atlantic Ocean (Box 19)
- Design for 12m Sloop for HSV, Sparkman & Stephens, 12/23/39 2/16/39 (Box 19)
- Mast Head Details, Feb. 15, 1939, Jan. 22, 1939 Jan. 30, 1939, Jan 22, 1939, Jan. 23, 1939, Feb. 9, 1939, Jan. 3, 1939 (Box 19)
- Article from the Wall Street Journal, Thursday, April 29, 1954. (Box 19)
- Letter from HSV to Stockholders of the Railroad Co. struggle. (Box 19)
- Large cup — "1900 Bryn Mawr Horse Show, Champion Pairs, Won by U.G.I, and B.G.I, and John L. Conaway." (Box 20)
- Small cup — "Bryn Mawr Horse Show, First Prize, High stepper, 1899" (Box 20)
- Cup — "Virginia Hot Springs, Special Match, mixed doubles, August 1946 Won by Mrs. Harold S. Vanderbilt and Bernon S. Prentice." (Box 20)
- Large cup — "Class 7, 1900. Bryn Mawr Horse Show, First Prize, Horse 14,2 not exceeding 15,3 Won by U.G.I. M.F.P. Conaway (Box 20)
- Bowl — Palm Beach tennis Club mixed doubles 1930 Runner-up (Box 20)
- Bryn Mawr Horse Show. First Prize. Horse 14,2 not exceeding 15,3, 1899 won by Mary F.P. Conaway. (Box 20)
- Small cup — Camp Pinecroft Swimming cup won by Gertrude L.P. Conaway, 1913 (Box 20)
- Cup — Bryn Mawr Horse Show 1900, High Stepping Class Presented by W.E. Carter. Won by U.G.I. John L. Conaway. (Box 20)
- Cup — 1899 Bryn Mawr Horse Show. First Prize Tandem Wheeler under 15, 1, Won by John L. Conaway (Box 20)
- Camp Pinecroft — True Sport Cup, .won by Gertrude L.P. Conaway, 1913. (Box 20)
- Model Plane (Box 21)
- Cup — 1901 Bryn Mawr Horse Show First Prize. Moet and Chandon Cup for Tandem Wheeler not to exceed 15 hands Won by (Box 21)
- large and small flags — blue and white with red star Plaque — Mrs. H.S. Vanderbilt. Member of the Society of Benefactors International Oceanographic Foundation Red leather, stamped book cover. (Box 22)
- Black and yellow ribbon with 'V' two paperweights. One H.S.V, another G.C.V., Mayor and Mayoress of Manalapan (Box 22)
- Four-pocket case for letter and bills, "G.C.V." (Box 22)
- Red Blotting Book, "H.S.V" (Box 22)
- Paperweight "With deep appreciation, Richard Nixon, Nov. 1972" (Box 22)
- Silver tobacco box with engraved map of the Convair Cruise, 1949 (Box 22)
- Metal, three-tiered cigarette case "Vanderbilt Cup Tournament, 1940" (Box 22)
- Hurricane lamp - "Versatile" Hand painted crystal vase Lantern, brass Brass tobacco box Two silver brushes. (Box 22)
- Hurricanelamp (Box 23)
- leather covered note-pad holder, "WKV" (Box 23)
- Silver plate Harold Stirling Vanderbilt, from his Godmother Julia Rhinelander Robert, Nov. 28, "1884" (Box 23)
- Two walnut tobacco boxes "HSV" (Box 23)
- clear star with the Presidential seal. Note from Richard Nixon accompanying (Box 23)
- Pewter tankard — Vanderbilt commodore Boosters, 1966 (Box 23)
- Two crystal ashtrays with HSV and pigs (Box 23)
- Leather rifle holder with strap (Box 23)
- Dark brown leather belt with brass buckle (Box 23)
- Blotter book, green leather. Silver-'"WKV" Six brass coasters "HSV" (Box 24)
- Six large silver glass holders-"Vagrant" (Box 24)
- Six small silver glass holders-"Vagrant" (Box 24)
- Silver soap dish-"HSV" (Box 24)
- Calendar in silver framejGCV (Box 24)
- Round tortoise shell hand mirror "GCV" (Box 24)
- Small ring box — was silk covered, picture inside (Box 24)
- Long pink leather pin box with jade stick pin (Box 24)
- Gold paper clip HSV (Box 24)
- Silver Spoon, CWT 1671 (Box 24)
- Twelve cuff links HSV (Six different pair) (Box 24)
- Two silver stars on red ribbon. One 1908, One 1906 Gertrude L.P. Conaway (Box 24)
- USNA pin 1920 (Box 24)
- Mechanical pencil Harold from Watson (Box 24)
- Jade stamp HSV (Box 24)
- Gold case "H S Vanderbilt Union Club, N.Y." in pink silk box (Box 24)
- Tortoise shell-handled brush Gold Ruler GCV (Box 24)
- Gold cigarette case with engravings (Box 24)
- Birthday note to Gertrude from Harold, 1968 (Box 24)
- Sketch of Harold S. Vanderbilt (several copies) Drawing of unknown man, 1916 (Box 25)
- Color print of the HSV portrait with wheel (Box 25)
- Engraved portrait of Commodore Vanderbilt Engraved portrait of Cornelius Vanderbilt II (Box 25)
- Print of "Bro Perrennial" George W. Lewis, 1921 (Box 25)
- Certificate of Appreciation from the World Bridge Federation Handpainted design. Pink leather covered board case. In white box. With letter 1969 (Box 25)
- Prints of Yachts (6) by Fred S. Cozzens, '83 In Down East Waters — Boston Bay — Syren Beetle, Countess, Halcyon, Phanton, Adelita, Sappho A Breezy day outside, Columbia, Sappho, Palmer Around the cape - Marblehead - Hera Fearless, Adrienne Gitaus, MonaShadow, Fannie Over the Cape May Course - 1873 - Sharp Shooter, Negus Reindeer, Clio, Preadnaught, Enchantress Rounding the Light Ship - Fanny, Gracie, Rover Before the Wind - Newport 1883 - Social, Vixen, Arrow, Permelia, Maggie (Box 25)
- Sanskrit verse print Ted Grohs, painting of Airplane, N12L Poem "Vagrant Thoughts" George H. Monsell Oil landscape (Box 25)
- Print of Airplane, N-159, (2) (Box 25)
- Photograph of Vagrant (Box 25)
- Picture of Yacht (Box 25)
- Color photo of courtyard (Box 25)
- Photo of yachts. Edwin Levick, N.Y. (Box 25)
- Autographed photo of George II, King of Greece, June 1942 (Box 25)
- Page from a French magazine, W./K. Vanderbilt wins Prix du Jockey-Club de 1909 (Box 25)
- Currier & Ives print Clipper Ship, Three Brothers (Box 25)
- World Bridge Federation tribute — Honorary Membership (Box 25)
- Metropolitan Museum of Art. G.C.Vanderbilt fellow for life (Box 25)
- Moonlanding stamp on poster. Signed by Nixon and Blount (Box 25)
- Drawing of Airplane Crmfpnt-s (Box 25)
- State of Pennsylvania - John L. Conaway - Battalion Adjutave (Box 25)
- Citation for a gift to Vanderbilt University, 1960 (Box 25)
- Time Club membership (Box 25)
- Honorary citizen of Metropolitan Nashville - Davidson County (Box 25)
- Rust's Modified Azimuth (Box 25)
- Arms for Medical School, Harvard University See correspondence, George Packer Berry (Box 25)
- Vanderbilt University 1966-70 Honorary National Chairman 55 Million for Vanderbilt Campaign (Box 25)
- Bridge cartoons "The War of Nerves" "Ya Won't B'lieve ... "Nov. 22 "Is this guy Vanderbilt Home?" May 9 Christmas The Deliberate Player (Box 25)
- Card from Sir Noel and Lady Mobbs (Box 25)
- Scrapbooks, 1930 America's Cup Race (Box 26)
- Scrapbooks, 1930 America's Cup Race Five boxes of photographs were removed to the Photographic Archive. These consisted of family snapshots, portraits, old scrapbooks of the Vanderbilt and Conaway families, Yachts, airplanes, Vanderbilt University. (Box 27)
- General Correspondence — Incoming
- Ammidon, Hoyt. June 1, 1970, with photograph
- Berry, George Packer., Feb. 16, 1966
- Blount, Winton M. July 20, 1970, see box 25 for enclosure Briley, Beverly., July 1, 1964
- Cecil, George H.V. June 11, 1970, with photos of portraits
- Dorsey, J.S. Aug. 28, 1962 Duchin, Peter., Oct. 4, 1962
- Ensko, Stephen., June 3, 1959; Sept. 16, 1968; Apr. 30, 1969
- Faulds, Captain., Oct. 10, 1971; Oct. 31, 1971; Oct. 10, 1972; Nov. 10, 1972 Finnigan, O.D., Jr. May 18, 1964 Fraser, Nancy, n.d.; June 9, 1964 Frey, Richard Sept. 23, 1968
- Kennedy, John., July 12, 1963
- Lindsay, John V., Nov. 12, 1965
- McCullough, R.W. May 27, 1972 Mara, W.A. March 25, 1941 Mosbacher, Emil (Bus), Oct. 5, 1962
- Orzech, Bernard P., Oct. 5, 1962
- Rockefeller, Nelson A., June 1, 1961
- Simon, John E. Dec. 19, 1969 Skouras, Spyros P. March 24, 1941 Smith, Suzanne A., Jan. 25, 1966
- Tavenner, Frank S., Jr. Jan. 26, 1963; May 16, 1963 Taylor, Arthur H., May 31, 1963
- Vanderbilt, Betty., Aug. 25, 1966
- Vanderbilt, William H., Sept. 26, 1941; Nov. 15, 1964; Jan. 14, 1965; June 17, 1970
- White, William., Dec. 7, 1961 Waugh, Elizabith L. Aug. 28, 1963 Winslow, John G. July 25, 1978 Wiren, Alexis. Jan. 17, 1964; Mar. 10, 1964 Woody, Kennedy. Nov. 15, 1965; Dec. 1, 1965
- General Correspondence Outgoing 1960: Nov. 15, Charles F. Walcett 1961: Jan. 9, William White
- Elizabith L. Waugh; Dec. 19, Mrs. Kennedy, 1963: Aug, 30
- Alexis R. Wiren; June 11, Nancy Fraser; July 13, Mayor Beverly Briley, 1964: Apr. 14
- Bill (William H. Vanderbilt); Nov. 16, Kennerly Woody; Dec. 3, K. Woody, 1965: Jan. 19
- 1966: Jan. 31, Sheldon V. Smith; March 3, George Packer Berry
- 1968: Jeb. 6, John Parkinson; Sept. 18, Stephen Ensko
- 1969: Feb. 24, Sam Fleming
- 1970: June 16, George V. Cecil; William H. Vanderbilt; June.22, W.H. Vanderbilt
- 1972: Oct. 18, Captain William Faulds
- Vanderbilt University Correspondence, General. Incoming
- Armistead, Parkes. June 8, ]959 Benedict, A.B., June 20, 1951
- Branscomb, Harvie., Jan. 28, 1955; Feb. 11, 1955; June 27, 1956; June 18, 1959
- Sept. 3, 1959; Mar. 9, 1962; July 2, 1962; Nov. 15, 1962; Jul 23, 1963; July 2, 1964 July 22, 1964; June 15, 1969
- Fleming, Sam M., Feb. 10, 1964
- Gardner, Edwin S. Dec. 30, 1963 Gasser, Roy C., July 2, 1956
- Heard, Alex., Oct. 24, 1963; July 2, 1964; Nov. 4, 1964; July 7, 1965 Houston, Frank K. June 24, 1959
- Kimball, Lindsley F., June 9, 1959
- McGaw, Robert A., Apr. 10, 1973
- Rusk, Dean., June 22, 1959
- Stambaugh, John H., June 9, 1959
- Stevenson, Alec B., June 11, 1959
- Stevenson, Eldon, Jr., July 2, 1962; July 24, 1959
- Sullivan, Walter., June 26, 1962; June 10, 1965; July 9, 1965
- Waller, William., June 8, 1959
- Bob —?—., Oct. 14, 1963
- Vanderbilt University Correspondence, General Outgoine
- Ralph A Gabriel, 1958: Oct. 29
- Harvie Branscomb; June 3, Dean Rusk; June 10, Branscomb; June 13, John H. Stambaugh; Lt. Graham Thompson; June 19, Branscomb; June 23, Frank Houston; June 25, Branscomb; Houston; William Waller, 1959: May 8
- Vanderbilt Relatives, 1969: Oct. 17
- Don R. Elliott; July 2, Prof. Sullivan; June 28, Branscomb, 1962: Jan. 3
- Branscomb; Feb. 13, Charles S. Churchill; July 13, Branscomb; Alexander Heard; Oct. 19, Robert Cutler, 1964: Apr. 2
- Mrs. John Tigert; July 2, Walter Sullivan; July 13, Heard, 1965: Feb. 23
- Heard, 1969: July 23
- Vanderbilt University Correspondence — Integration, Incoming
- Beach, Leonard B., May 8, 1962
- Bloch, Ingram., May 14, 1962
- Branscomb, Harvie., March 26, 1962; March 29, 1962; April 4, 1962
- Darby, William., April 26, 1962
- Stevenson, Alec B., May 18, 1962
- Wade, John W., April 4, 1962
- Vanderbilt University Correspondence — Integration, Outgoing
- 1962: March 19, Harvie Branscomb; Mar 28, Branscomb; Apr 2, Henry C. Alexander; Branscomb; Apr 6, John W. Wade; Apr 24, Branscomb; Apr 26, Alexander; May 23, Ingram Bloch; Apr 27, Staumbough; Apr. 28, Branscomb; Apr 30, Eldon Stevenson; May 23, Alec B Stevenson
- Vanderbilt University Correspondence — Selection of a Chancellor, Incoming
- Beach, Leonard. Feb. 28, 1962, June 21, 1962
- Boren, J.L., June 4, 1962
- Bottamiller, Irene., June 26, 1962
- Branscomb, Harvie., May 16, 1962; June 4; June 7; June 13; June 29; 1962
- Christie, Amos., July 25, 1961 Elliott, Don. June 20, 1962
- Fleming, Sam M., April 2, 1962
- Heard, Alexander., April 2, 1962; Apr. 21, 1962; May 2, 1962; July 12; Luly 21, 1962
- Houston, George M., June 4, 1962 (telegram)
- Hyatt, J. Philip., July 25, 1961
- Jackson, Baxter., June 4, 1962
- Jewell, W.B., July 2, 1961; Sept. 14, 1961; Jan. 5, 1962; May 20, 1962
- Johnson, Jesse E., June 5, 1962; June 25, 1962